[instrumental music]
[Jane]
Oh, it's lovely.
[Lisbon]
It's a crime scene.
[Patrick]
It's a lovely crime scene.
[Rigsby]
Hey, couple joggers
found our John Doe
on their morning run.
Body's still pretty fresh.
It must have happened
last night.
No signs of an entry
or exit wound.
It means cause was probably a
blunt force trauma to the head.
And they brought
in the grown-ups
because they couldn't
decide whose sandbox it was?
Right, body's right
on the city line.
'The only thing
they canagree on'
'is that it was a carjacking
gone wrong.'
Wallet, watch, wedding band,
everything gone.
Oh, not everything.
Killer would have been
very frustrated
'to not be able to take this.'
It looks like a wheel.
Motorcycle wheel.
I don't buy it as a carjacking.
'Maybe the murderer
was covering it up as one'
but if you're after someone's
car and valuables
you grab and bolt.
'You don't waste time
taking off a cufflink.'
Right, carjacking,
a gunshot or a stab wound
is more likely than a beating.
Beating like this
takes time.
The murder was personal.
No surprise there.
The haircut,
the suit, the cologne.
This man had enemies.
His cologne tells you
he had enemies?
Sure.
Okay, confrontational.
Finishing touch
on a wardrobe that says
"Pay attention.
Show respect."
This was an extrovert,
tough guy, a professional.
A backroom politician
or a lawyer, a fixer.
'The type that's good
with people.'
Makin' people do things
they maybe don't wanna do.
Uh, what he is, is useless
until we know whohe is.
Well, I can do that too.
Oh, no, Jane. I, uh, I checked.
The phone's not on him--
The signal light's still on.
Phone's in range.
His assailant probably
threw it in the trees.
What are you doing?
I'm makin' a call.
But you don't have
the phone.
- I have my voice.
- You still need the phone.
Wanna use the voice activation?
You need its names and numbers.
There is one name
programmed into every phone
particularly into one
belonging to a middle-aged man
that was wearing
a wedding band.
Home.
[phone ringing]
[female #1]
'Hello?'
Hello,
this is Patrick Jane
from the California Bureau
of Investigation.
I was wondering if you knew
a man six feet tall, mid 40s
salt and pepper hair,
gray custom-made suit
weighing about 192,
give or take?
[female #1]
'That's my husband
Gordon Hodge.'
- Gordon Hodge?
- 'You said you're from CBI?'
'Is something wrong?'
Uh, just a sec.
It's for you.
Hello?
[theme music]
[instrumental music]
[doorbell ringing]
[Mrs. Hodge]
I knew that something like this
would happen sooner or later.
[Lisbon]
Well, was your husband having
some sort of trouble lately?
Gordon was a criminal attorney
with a very special practice.
He had only one client,
the Sinner Saints.
- Bikers, are they?
- Yeah.
They're one of the top
biker gangs in the state.
They run some legit businesses,
but mostly
they're into drugs
and prostitution
'low-rent protection rackets,
that kind of thing.'
[Mrs. Hodge]
'For years, I begged
him to get out'
'but Gordon said that'
'a lawyer never abandons
his client.'
It's unethical.
It's what he always
called them.
Never the gang,
always the client.
When was the last time
you saw him?
[Mrs. Hodge]
'Yesterday morning,
before work.'
Gordon used to meet
these people at all hours.
That's how they are.
So, we didn't get worried
'when he didn't come home
last night.'
Had he been acting
differently lately?
He'd been more on edge
the last week or so.
I think something happened
at work, but I'm not sure what.
Did you ask him
about it?
No, never.
Work was off limits.
He said it was boring.
What was the real reason?
Do you think he was ashamed,
or he sensed your shame?
He wanted to protect us.
Would his colleagues
at the office
have known
what was going on?
No, he was a one-man shop.
Didn't even have a secretary.
'Gordon didn't trust anyone
with his business.'
[Lisbon]
'Any idea who might
have wanted to kill him?'
Well, you might wanna
ask his client.
He knew all their secrets.
He probably learned something
that he shouldn't have.
Either of you ever meet
any of those scumbags?
No.
You two must be very torn.
Living in such a beautiful home.
'Driving nice cars,
going to good schools.'
All paid for
by dangerous criminals
or, uh, scumbags,
as my colleague says.
Do I wish that Gordon would have
defended civil rights leaders?
Yes, of course!
'But he believed that everyone
had a constitutional right'
to have a good defense.
He had his principles.
Thank you for your time.
Did you go to some interview
school I've never heard of?
Next time, get the facts,
save the editorial.
Yes, ma'am.
I know,Jane did it too.
He's not a CBI agent.
From you, I expect
professional standards.
Yes, boss.
That was the captain
of the local CHIPS.
Hodge's car was just
fished out of a lake
about a mile
from the murder scene.
No good for prints.
'He said that two weeks back'
'they busted Hodge
at a highway rest stop'
walkin' to his car
with two ounces of coke
and two ounces
of meth in his pockets.
Nailed him
with felony possession.
Nice.
Only the DA dropped the charges.
'There was some
unlawful search technicality.'
[Lisbon]
'Either Hodge
is a great lawyer..'
Or the DA turned him
in exchange for dropping
the charges, planned to
use him as an informant.
- Well if the Saints found out--
- Yeah, they'd kill him.
They didknow about the charges.
Their boss, Von McBride,
posted Hodge's bail.
[Lisbon]
'Well, talk to your friends
at the DA.'
Find out what
the story is there.
Jane and I'll go talk
to the Sinner Saints.
- Okay, be careful.
- Want me to come for backup?
Uh, no. Talk to forensics
about the car.
Jane, let's go.
Now, please?
Come on.
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
- Beautiful, huh?
- No, not really.
I fail to see the charm.
It's the glamour
of mobility.
That's why the girls
went for Cain, and not Abel.
- Is that right?
- Yeah, nomads.
Sexier than farmers.
They have romance.
[cell phone ringing]
Lisbon.
I spoke to my friend
in the DA's office.
They didn't make
a deal with Hodge.
'They let him go because
the case was less than ironclad'
and they've already lost too
many to Hodge and the Saints.
Last ten years, they've beaten
the rap in over 50 cases.
Murder, rape, drug trafficking.
They're bulletproof.
Nobody's bulletproof.
Well, the DA says
to stay away from them.
'They're bad news.'
Good, sound lawyerly advice.
I'll take that
under advisement.
- You ready?
- Whoo.
[heavy metal music]
There's romance for you.
We're with the CBI.
We're looking
for Von McBride.
Not here, which is where
you need to be.
Well, can you tell us
where he is?
No, I cannot.
[Lisbon]
Listen, we're here
for information.
'Not trouble, guys.'
[male #1]
'Well, we've got nothing
to say.'
[Lisbon]
'I can take you in
if you want me to.'
'I prefer to talk here.'
[male #1]
'Like I said'
'we've got nothin'
to talk about.'
'We're not doing
anythin' illegal.'
Mr. McBride?
Your focus
on this pressing matter
suggests you're the man
in charge here.
Yeah, well,
keep on walking, blondie.
We just have a few questions
for you. It won't take long.
Yeah, well, I'm sorry, I don't,
uh, talk to police officers
on the advice of my lawyer.
Your lawyer's dead.
Yeah, I heard that.
But his advice is still good.
Means your business here
is done.
Oh, you don't wanna know
who the informant is then?
What informant?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Forget I spoke.
I'm so sorry.
You messin' with me?
Yeah, I'm messing with you.
There's no informant.
Come here.
You touch him,
and I'll arrest you.
I would loveto see you
try and do that.
What's your name?
- Xander.
Your threats are empty.
She's a state agent.
You're not gonna lay
a finger on her
'and you know that,
so why play tough?'
W-where's that come from?
This need to intimidate?
I'm a sadist,
and I bore easily.
Oh, me, I see
a difficult childhood.
Bad parenting,
a lot of torment.
But I also see how
that suffering gave you
great powers of empathy
and a strong creative side.
And those are the qualities
you should try
and nurture in yourself.
Not this brutish character
you try to hide behind.
Oh, that's Xander, alright.
Full of empathy.
You guys want a drink?
Sure.
So what's this crap
about an informant?
How long have you known about
Hodge's taste for coke and meth?
Couple of years.
Guy liked to party,
but he could still do his job.
[Jane]
Couldn't have been too thrilled
when he got busted.
Case got dropped.
Must have wondered why.
Illegal search.
Yeah.
Either that or Hodge,
uh, flipped on you.
- That son of a--
- Hold on a second, Diamond.
He didn't flip.
There is no informant.
Where were you last night?
Right here.
And I got 30 other brothers
who will vouch for me
and each other.
Look, man,
none of my guys did this.
We loved Gordon, man. He was
like a member of the club.
Yeah, he couldn't ride
worth a damn.
No, he couldn't, huh?
He tried though.
Then, who killed him?
[McBride]
'My guess?'
Probably some other
motorcycle club
looking to put us
out of business.
Chaos Brigade.
Bolos Plata.
[female #2]
'Get your hands
off of me.'
'Get off me.'
Help! Get your hands
off of me.
Get off of me.
Let her go,
and back away!
- Back away now!
- Get your hands off me.
You're murderers.
All of you.
Ma'am, take it easy.
I'm CBI.
Ma'am!
Police. Stop!
Out of the way.
Ma'am!
[dramatic music]
Who was that?
Is she a friend of yours?
Never seen her before.
Mentally deranged,
seems like. Poor thing.
You know,
you're a very good liar.
Most people subconsciously
signal dishonesty
but you, there's nothing.
No inner conflict.
Usually, that's the mark
of what shrinks
like to call a sociopath.
Well, if by sociopath,
you mean that if you cross me
I would enjoy watching you
suffer pain before I kill you..
...then, yeah,
I'm a sociopath.
See ya.
Bye.
[Rigsby]
So, we talked
to the gang unit.
There's no other biker gang
that would cross the Saints
and run the risk of starting
a war that they couldn't win.
[Jane]
This is incredible.
You should see this.
Hold on. Anything on
the woman in the parking lot?
Sinner Saints
have their own website.
- Really?
- Yeah.
We cross-checked registrations
of the truck model and color
with driver's license photos
fitting her description.
No hits, truck must be
registered to her husband
or other family member.
McBride's clamming up about her
means he's hiding something.
He's merged two other gangs
into the Saints
in the last five years.
It's the fastest growing gang
in the nation.
Go to Hodge's office,
see if you can find
anything on the gang's
operation that pops.
And have the Deerfield PD
issue a BOLO
on the woman's pickup truck.
- Right.
- You can buy logo merchandise.
Sinner Saints coffee mugs,
decals, beach towels. Whoa!
And some various other
interesting little knick-knacks.
- Nice.
- Yeah.
Well, if they do it,
we should do it.
A range of casual wear, maybe?
Sensible shoes?
I'll get right on that.
Lisbon loafers.
Found something, boss.
These are Gordon Hodge's
cell phone calls
from the night
of the murder.
All were routine business calls
Von McBride, other lawyers,
court officials.
'But it's the last call
that bumps.'
"7:23, incoming
from a Constance Hoyt.
Current address unknown."
Must not want people
finding her.
Well, I went back
three months.
A lot of calls
between her and Hodge.
- Did you try the number?
- Twice.
Got one of those
computer voicemail messages.
Plus, I ran her name
through the DMV
for registration
of a black pickup truck.
She's not
your parking lot woman.
Check Von McBride's
cell phone records.
See if he had any contact
with this Constance Hoyt.
Bingo.
Couple of chatty Cathys.
Talking three
or four times a day.
Either she's his mom, or..
His girlfriend.
[heavy metal music]
Constance?
We just have a couple
questions for you.
[motorcycle whirring]
Constance.
- I'll drive.
- No time!
[dramatic music]
- Boss, seat belt.
- Go!
[music continues]
[tires screeching]
Bike's got too much muscle.
You're gonna have to..
[music continues]
[grunting]
[Van Pelt]
'Don't move.'
[Lisbon]
'Keep your hands
where I can see 'em.'
Do not even think
of moving.
I gotta get you
out of the office more.
You're under arrest.
You got Hodge's office key?
So what's your problem
with bikers?
- I hate bikers.
- Why's that?
- My dad was a biker.
- Really?
I didn't know that.
No? Well, I thought
you read my file.
Well, it says
he was a big-time criminal.
Didn't specify
any affiliations.
Jimmy marks on the doorknob.
I doubt that was part
of the original decor.
[dramatic music]
- Door's clear.
- Clear.
The desk's clear.
[sighs]
Cracks are on the outside
of the window.
It means a previous
break-in attempt.
'I think they were looking
for something'
or just trying
to send a message?
Message was definitely
a part of it.
Do you prefer Constance,
or Diamond?
I prefer to get
the hell out of here.
You ran from the police.
Endangered the lives
of two agents.
You could be here
a couple of days.
- I don't think that's right.
- Why did you run?
I ran because I'm deadif
anyone sees me talking to cops.
The Saints are all paranoid
about informants now
which is why
I'm not saying a word.
Tell us about your affair
with Gordon Hodge.
[scoffs]
I wasn't sleeping with Gordon.
Oh!
Uh, yes, you were.
It was only a few months.
We were just having fun.
It's not like Von doesn't
sleep around on me and..
Gordon treated me nice.
You had genuine feelings
for him.
He was decent.
He never looked down
on you.
He just got sucked in
too deep with the Saints.
Did you know
he was arrested for possession?
Told him a hundred times
to be careful..
...but he got dumb
about it.
Ah, well, drugs simply
make people careless.
You had to be a little concerned
about McBride finding out.
It would have made things
complicated.
Complicated is one way
to put it.
So you called him that night.
Then what happened?
- Did you go and see him?
- No!
No.
I called to break it off.
I heard him answer the phone.
And I'd tried to talk to him,
but the line went dead.
What about the woman
in the parking lot?
I don't know.
Von doesn't talk
gang business with me.
Had you seen her before?
She's come around
a few times
the last couple of weeks,
same thing.
Lots of crazy yelling,
then taking off.
Look..
You, um..
You gotta promise
that Von doesn't find out
about me and Gordon.
He keeps his cards close.
He could already know.
'Killed Hodge
out of jealousy.'
Trust me.
If Von knew..
...Gordon's wouldn't be
the only dead body.
Only one other person knew.
And that was bad enough.
Who was that other person?
We have information
that suggests
you knew about Gordon
and another woman.
Yes, I did.
How?
About four months ago,
I found a valet stub
on the driveway
from the Deerfield Inn.
So one night,
I followed him
and saw him go in
with that biker girl.
Did you confront him?
More like yell and hit him.
He promised
he'd stop seeing her.
I took him at his word
and I never asked him
about it again.
Why not?
Because I didn't wanna
hear him lie to me.
Mrs. Hodge..
...if you picked up
on your husband's affair
you must have suspected about
his other illicit activities.
I knew about the drugs
and the partying.
He was surrounded by it.
Why didn't you tell us
about this earlier?
Because Gordon is dead.
Anything that I said or did
would not bring him back.
My son draws stares
and whispers
'because of his father,
Agent Lisbon.'
Both of us,
we deserve to grieve
without shame and scandal,
don't we?
Yes, you do.
And if she'd followed
her husband once before
she could have tailed him again
and killed him.
No, she didn't do it.
She loved him.
She was a prisoner
of her husband's life.
She gets rid of him,
gets a fresh start.
People trapped
in miserable lives
always talk about escaping.
Few actually do it.
It's easier just
to close your eyes
and pretend the misery
doesn't exist.
[knocking]
Boss, you might wanna see this.
[Cho]
This is from a security camera
across the street.
It was the third incident
in two weeks.
Building owner said Hodge didn't
wanna report the earlier ones
'because he didn't want
Deerfield PD combing through'
his office and accidentally
finding something
in his Sinner Saints file.
There.
Magnify.
'The woman
from the parking lot?'
She certainly gets around.
[instrumental music]
[indistinct chatter]
[McBride]
'Chaos Brigade
controls distribution'
over in Rancho Rosa,
but I figure if we move
'right now, we can
move into Stratton--'
What's up, my brothers?
[clears throat]
We just have one quick
follow-up question for you.
I've exceeded my quota
of answering cops' questions.
And my quota of crazy.
The woman,
in the parking lot.
Uh, like I said,
she must have mistaken me--
She was seen vandalizing
Hodge's office.
She find anything
she shouldn't have?
His files were intact.
She got nothing.
We have nothing further
to talk about, then.
The sooner this case is closed,
the sooner we're gone
and you're back
to business as usual.
[instrumental music]
Last name is Guthrie.
She's the sister of a gentleman
I was accused of killing.
Falsely, of course.
'Trial was a couple
of weeks ago.'
Gordon hit a home run.
Got me off.
And you weren't eager
to ID her
because you didn't want us
poking around your case?
Hey, all I know is
that she's been coming around
from time to time, saying
some very offensive things.
Thanks for your cooperation.
You think she killed Gordon?
Like I said,
thanks for your cooperation.
I've got one last question.
If Hodge wasn't the informant
in your gang..
...who do you think it is?
I mean,
I tried asking the DA
but he's kind of
a secretive bastard, huh?
What do you think?
Mr. Jane,
we're a motorcycle club.
Not a gang.
And I can assure you
there is no informant.
Well, you'd know best.
Why does he keep going on
about this informant?
He's just talking.
Let's get down to business.
So, Miss Guthrie?
Von McBride should be
sitting here, not me.
Court docs say your brother,
Rick was an auto mechanic.
McBride blamed him
for screwing up a repair
and your brother
refused to redo it.
McBride allegedly got angry
and killed him.
Not allegedly.
He killed him.
He beat him to death
with a crowbar.
- He murdered him.
- And the jury disagreed.
McBride acted
in self-defense, right?
That's because
that lawyer, Hodge
made it look like
it was my brother's fault.
He started throwing around
all these lies about my brother.
Saying that my brother
was a druggie.
That he was aggressive.
That he was mentally unstable.
So you get all worked up,
harass the gang
trash Hodge's office,
right?
You wanna arrest me
for that. Go ahead.
I'm not gonna fight you.
I'm too tired.
You ever try Hodge's home?
Once.
But his kid came outside.
I don't have a beef with him.
So I took off
before I could do anything.
And what were you gonna do?
I don't know.
I was..
I wanted Hodge
to understand
what he had done to me
and to my family.
And when was this?
- Two days ago.
- The day of the murder.
- Where were you that night?
- Home.
Can anyone verify it?
I live alone,
but I didn't--
Now, six months ago
you were arrested
in a road rage incident.
Got out of your car
at a red light.
Attacked a man
in an SUV.
What does this have
to do with anything?
You're an angry person
and you express it physically.
I'm not angry.
I am sad.
My brother was a good man.
The only crime he committed
was standing up
to that bastard, McBride.
Hodge blackens the name
of your dead brother
and gets Von McBride off.
'Now maybe trashing his office'
'didn't give you
enough satisfaction.'
Perfectly understandable
if your frustration boils over.
And you can't touch Von McBride.
He's got 20 bikers around him
all the time.
So maybe you go
for the easier target.
I didn't kill Gordon Hodge.
But I'm sure as hell
glad that he's dead.
[Cho]
She'd been to his house
that day.
Could have laid in wait
and followed him later.
Plus, she was out for revenge,
no more powerful motive.
We don't have nearly enough
to charge her.
I say we hold her
on the vandalism.
Try to dig up something that
puts her at the murder scene.
Or you could release her.
She's obviously impulsive
and sloppy enough
'to get caught on camera.'
She'll think
she's bought herself some time.
And she'd try something
to cover her tracks
and implicate herself.
Cut her loose,
then let's shadow her.
Yes, boss.
[sighs]
Where are you going?
Fresh air.
All this murder talk..
"...is rank.
It stinks to heaven.
It hath the primal
eldest curse upon 't."
Shakespeare.
[instrumental music]
[tires screeching]
Little less pressure
on the brake pedal.
Is your mom here?
Market. That's why
I'm confined to the driveway.
Ah!
You want me
to have her call you?
We know Felicia Guthrie
trespassed on the property
the day your dad was killed.
I-I just need to hear
what happened.
Uh, I was leaving for school.
I saw her hop the gate and come
running up the driveway.
So I ran out
to try to stop her.
And she was yelling
all this stuff about my dad
lying about her brother
and getting Von McBride off.
- Then she just ran away.
- Did your parents see her?
No. Dad was already at work,
and mom was in the shower.
Huh. Any reason you didn't
bring this up earlier?
I don't know. I felt
bad for her, I guess.
Didn't want her
to get in trouble.
Well, just needed
to confirm. Thanks.
[engine grinds]
Whoa!
God!
You need to relax.
It's not gonna help. I'm never
gonna get the hang of this.
That's an easy fix.
You need the right instructor.
Alright, so now you can
speed up a little.
'Excellent. I like how
you're keeping your distance.'
Just trust your instincts.
They're always right.
You're a good instructor.
Yeah, I am,
probably because I have
zero emotional investment
in how you do.
Unlike your father
who I'm guessing
got annoyed
with every mistake you made.
He wasn't the most patient guy.
Probably didn't help that
he was always on his cell phone.
I've been living with his job
my whole life.
You get used to it.
You also get used to the drugs
and the cheating
on your mother?
He promised he'd stop.
Yeah.
Can't be easy
going through life
being labeled
the gang lawyer's son.
It wasn't really that bad.
I mean, girls would come
up to me all the time.
Talk to me about dad
and the gang, like I'm cool.
Instead of a geek,
which I basically am.
Everybody is.
I am.
If he was my father,
I tell ya, I-I..
...I'd be mad at him.
Dad didn't mean
to hurt anyone.
- He was just doing his job.
- Right.
Well, I guess I'd still
love him if he was my father.
Can't say I'd cut him
the same kind of slack
if I was married to him.
Are you trying
to blame my mom?
- 'Cause if you are..
- What?
You're wrong, that's all.
She loved him too.
Well, that brings us
back to Felicia Guthrie
who didn't love him at all.
What exactly did she say
to you when you saw her?
It was hard to tell.
She was just, you know,
ranting, basically.
Didn't make much sense.
Very nicely done.
You'll be out cruising
on Saturday nights in no time.
Just remember,
trust your instincts.
They're always right.
Thank you.
And thanks for
the driving lesson.
Yeah.
[dogs barking]
Still no movement.
Looks like Miss Guthrie's
in for the night.
Talk to Van Pelt recently?
Yep.
- Any progress?
- Nope.
[engine rumbling in distance]
You hear that?
Yeah.
[dramatic music]
They're gonna go
after Felicia.
McBride thinks
she killed Hodge.
He wants payback.
Officers on Hampton,
North of Lexington
request
immediate assistance.
[music continues]
What the hell's going on?
Go back in your house
and stay down.
[music continues]
Do the smart thing
and get out of here right now.
We're not doing
anything illegal.
Disorderly conduct
concealed weapons,
blown exhaust pipes
probably a couple of
outstanding warrants in there.
- 'Screw you, pig!'
- 'No, screw you!'
We could bust
half you clowns right now.
So what's it gonna be?
[music continues]
We'll be seeing you around.
[engines revving]
[indistinct yelling]
Scumbag!
[laughing]
You really don't like bikers.
[Felicia]
'If they think they can
intimidate me, they're wrong.'
Felicia, temperatures
are running hot
so I need you to stay away
from the gang's bar from now on.
[Felicia]
'Yeah. I'll stay away
when you arrest Von McBride.'
And what were you people
doing out here, anyway?
Oh, we think you killed,
uh, Gordon Hodge
so Agent Cho and Rigsby
have been watching you.
Oh, come on,
she was never gonna buy
"We just happened to be
in the neighborhood."
I told you I had nothing
to do with that.
And who told you
that you could go in my house?
Oh, this? I just needed
some tea. Cut through the chill.
Chill, my ass.
You were looking for evidence.
- Felicia, take it easy.
- Don't tell me to take it easy.
When this guy's rifling
through my underwear drawer
looking for a weapon.
It was your closet, actually,
I was looking
for blood-splattered shoes.
- Get off my property.
- You're very touchy.
Go.
You really looked
through her closet?
Laundry, too.
She's been angry and emotional
about her brother.
Which means
that she was sloppy
about Hodge's murder.
Dragged evidence
home with her.
It's just not inside.
Well, there's no garage
or toolshed.
Well, I looked everywhere.
Well, everywhere
except the...garbage.
Why not?
Well, it's garbage.
- Are you done with that?
- Almost.
Yes, the case
is still ongoing
and you are
a person of interest.
'I'd advise you
not to leave town.'
Boss?
Excuse me.
Do you see that?
What's goin' on?
Stay there. Don't move.
[Rigsby]
It's the victim's
missing cufflink.
I didn't do anything wrong.
McBride must have set me up.
Rigsby, put her
in interview one.
Boss, Nina and Lucas Hodge
are here to see you.
- Did she say why?
- 'Cause I asked them down here.
Rigsby, could you bring her
through here, please?
It will just take a minute.
Thank you.
Are you gonna tell me
what this is about?
I'm just closing
your case.
Thanks for coming down,
Mrs. Hodge.
This woman's name
is Felicia Guthrie.
She murdered your husband
out of revenge for getting
Von McBride off a charge
for killing her brother.
- Oh, my God!
- No, I did not kill anyone--
Uh, we have evidence.
We just need
your permission for, uh..
...Lucas to make a formal
statement, saying that
he saw her at your house
the day of the murder.
- You saw her?
- He can fill you in later.
His statement will give us
a better chance at a conviction.
- Absolutely. Anything you need.
- Great. Thank you.
Lucas, if you can confirm
that this is who you saw
then you'll be on your way.
What's gonna happen to her?
Well, probably life in prison.
Uh, if she's lucky, she might
get paroled in 25 years.
No! I swear, I didn't..
- I didn't touch him--
- 'Shut up!'
You took everything from us.
Lucas, we need to book her now,
so could you identify her?
No, she wasn't the one.
I mean, yeah,
she came to the house--
Great. Thanks.
That's all we need.
- Take her away, guys.
- 'No, I didn't do anything.'
- Thank you.
- 'I didn't do anything wrong.'
Trust your instincts, Lucas.
They're always right.
[Felicia]
'I'm telling the truth!'
Let's go.
- She couldn't have done it.
- What makes you say that?
- I just know.
- 'Lucas, they have evidence.'
- This bitch killed your--
- Don't call her that.
It wasn't her.
The only way we can know
for certain is if
you tell us who did it.
Okay, stop talking to my son.
You've got your statement.
Lucas, let's go.
- 'Come on. Let's go.'
- No.
- Lucas--
- Stop.
It was me.
We were out
for a driving lesson.
I was driving badly
that night.
My dad was on the phone
the whole time
like he always was.
He'd get mad every time
I'd make a mistake but..
...I just couldn't seem
to concentrate.
Because of your run-in
with Felicia Guthrie that day?
You didn't talk about her
until I asked
'cause you felt sorry for her.
You didn't wanna draw
suspicion to her
because you knew
she didn't do it.
You were trying to do
the right thing.
I just kept seeing her
in the driveway.
Crying, yelling about how
my dad lied about her brother.
His phone just kept ringing.
And he'd get mad at me
and I'd screw up worse.
And I just..
I couldn't take it anymore.
Next time, his phone rang..
...I grabbed it from him.
I heard her voice.
[Constance]
Hey, Gordon, baby,
it's me. Can you talk?
That biker bitch,
Diamond.
'She kept calling him
Gordon, baby.'
'Said she really
wanted to see him.'
Felicia Guthrie was right.
He was a liar.
I threw the phone into the
woods, and he got really mad.
He promised me he'd stop.
Doing drugs
and cheating on my mom.
Like an idiot,
I believed him.
[grunting]
I called my mom.
She told me what to do.
'I took all the stuff
to make it look like a robbery'
but I couldn't get
that damn cufflink out.
'So I ditched his car
in the lake.'
She drove me home.
The lie gets heavy fast,
doesn't it?
I expect after a while
you wanted to go to the police
and tell them the truth.
Sometimes I wanted to.
Mom said no.
She promised
it would be okay.
Well, it might be..
...someday.
Let's go.
Put your hand out.
I'm sorry, mom.
[Van Pelt]
'Mrs. Hodge,
we need to talk now.'
[instrumental music]
You know, I have to wonder
how that cufflink Rigsby found
made its way
to Felicia Guthrie's house.
That is a conundrum.
Because I'll bet
a year's salary
that if I look
in the evidence locker
the cufflink we found on Hodge
will have mysteriously vanished.
Okay.
I needed Lucas to see
Felicia get arrested.
You needed hard evidence
to charge Felicia.
So..
...I made it happen.
By making
an innocent woman think
she was gonna go
to prison?
As if her life wasn't
hard enough already.
Yes, you're right.
She doesdeserve some justice.
It's good to see
you care.
You know, sarcasm
is the lowest form of wit?
[heavy metal music]
...next Tuesday,
we need about..
...about six, ten bikes.
- So be here--
- Yeah.
[phone ringing]
This will be our real gig.
Hold on.
Yeah?
Alright.
I'll be back in a minute.
[Jane]
'Hey, psst.'
'Over here.'
What's up?
Uh, I just thought
you might wanna know
we caught
Gordon Hodge's killer.
It was his son.
Lot of issues between 'em.
And you felt the need to tell
me this from the shadows
dressed in this get-up?
Self-preservation.
I figured I've worn out
my welcome with your friends.
That's it?
This is what
you had to tell me?
Well, no.
There's, uh, another reason.
You open that envelope..
...and the rat in your gang
will be revealed.
Oh, the rat.
[door opening]
Now turn around and try
not to look too guilty.
What was that about?
What, this?
This is, uh..
[chuckles]
It's kind of funny,
actually.
Funny?
[dramatic music]
Selling us out is funny?
- Hey! Hey!
- Come on, get him inside.
[McBride]
'Hey! Let go, man!'
[instrumental music]
I was set up!
[music continues]
[Jane]
Stay tuned for scenes
from our next episode.
[theme music]